Guide to the Richard Wright Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1934-1975; Series II; 7.5; (18 boxes)
  - PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Diesback, Sébastien de, 1955, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1295)
    - Dillard, Mabel, 1944-45 (Box 96, Folder 1296)
    - Diop, Alioune
    - Direction, 1943, 1946 (Box 96, Folder 1297)
    - Dissent, 1955-60 (Box 96, Folder 1298)
    - Dodson, Owen, 1940-59 (Box 96, Folder 1299)
    - Domestic Workers Union, 1940 (Box 96, Folder 1300)
    - Doubleday & Co., Inc., 1938-60 (Box 96, Folder 1301)
    - Drake, St. Clair, 19[45?]-55 (Box 96, Folder 1302)
    - Dreyfus, Rémi Daniel, 1947-59 (Box 96, Folder 1303)
    - Drudi, Lucia
    - Duhamel, Marcel, 1945, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1304)
    - "E" general, 1937-60 (Box 97, Folder 1305)
    - Ebony
      See: Johnson Publishing Company, Box 100, folder 1412
    - Eddy, Sherwood, 1945 (Box 97, Folder 1306)
    - Edes, Kenneth L., [1953] (Box 97, Folder 1307)
    - Editions Corréa & Cie, 1946-61 (Box 97, Folder 1308)
    - Editions de Flore, 1947-48 (Box 97, Folder 1309)
    - Editions Michel Albin, 1946-60 (Box 97, Folder 1310)
    - Editions Mondiales, 1955-60 (Box 97, Folder 1311)
    - Edwards, Elizabeth Ann, 1951 (Box 97, Folder 1312)
      See also: Series III, Franco-American Fellowship, Box 115, folder 1823
    - Ellington, Duke, 1942, 1944 (Box 97, Folder 1313)
    - Ellison, Ralph, 1937-53 (Box 97, Folder 1314)
    - Embree, Edwin, 1943-45 (Box 97, Folder 1315)
    - Entertainment Industry Emergency Committee, 1943-44 (Box 97, Folder 1316)
    - Ermilov, Vladimir, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1317)
    - Esquire, 1935, 1957, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1318)
    - Eugene F. Saxton Memorial Trust, 1945 (Box 97, Folder 1319)
    - "F" general, 1939-60 (Box 97, Folder 1320-1321)
    - Fabio Coen Agenzia Letteraria, 1947-58 (Box 97, Folder 1322)
    - Falardeau, Jean-Charles, 1945-49 (Box 97, Folder 1323)
    - Fanon, Frantz, 1953 Jan 6 (Box 97, Folder 1324)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1942, 1944 (Box 97, Folder 1325)
    - Farrar, Straus and Company, Inc., 1950 (Box 97, Folder 1326)
    - Farrell, James, 1935-47 (Box 97, Folder 1327)
    - Faulkner, William, 1956, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1328)
    - Fauset, Arthur, 1938-41 (Box 97, Folder 1329)
    - Federal Theater Project for New York, 1938-39 (Box 97, Folder 1330)
    - Federal Writers' Project, 1935-40 (Box 97, Folder 1331)
    - Field, Marshall, 1944-45 (Box 97, Folder 1332)
    - Fischer, John
    - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1944-45 (Box 97, Folder 1333)
    - Flye, Jesse T., 1940, 1946, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1334)
    - Foley, Martha
    - Folsom, Franklin
      See: League of American Writers, Box 100, folder 1435
    - Ford, Charles Henri
      See: View, Box 107, folder 1660
    - Ford, James W., 1938-42 (Box 97, Folder 1335)
    - Foreign Commission of the Union of Soviet Writers of the U.S.S.R., 1938-[44] (Box 97, Folder 1336)
    - Franco-American Fellowship, 1950-52 (Box 97, Folder 1337)
    - Frank, Waldo, 1945, 1947 (Box 97, Folder 1338)
    - Frasconi, Antonio and Renata [Renée], 1943-45 (Box 97, Folder 1339)
    - Frazier, Edward Franklin, 1959-60 (Box 97, Folder 1340)
    - Freund, Gisèle, 1950, 1958 (Box 97, Folder 1341)
    - Frey, Anne, 1956, 1958, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1342)
    - Friede, Donald
      See: World Publishing Company, Box 108, folder 1697
    - Frings, Ketti, 1958-60 (Box 97, Folder 1343)
    - Fuentes, Carlos, 1956 Feb 27 (Box 97, Folder 1344)
    - "G" general, 1936-60 (Box 97, Folder 1345-1346)
    - Galignani Librairie, 1949-54 (Box 98, Folder 1347)
    - Gatheru, R. Mugo, 1959-60 (Box 98, Folder 1348)
    - George Allen & Unwin, Ltd., 1957-58 (Box 98, Folder 1349)
    - Gibson, Richard, 1955, 1960 (Box 98, Folder 1350)
    - Gillett-Gatty, Katherine, 1939-40 (Box 98, Folder 1351)
    - Glover, Guy, 1942-45, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1352)
      See also: Norman McLaren, Box 101, folder 1462
    - Goll, Claire, 1940-48 (Box 98, Folder 1353)
    - Gold, Mike (draft of letter to Gold from Richard Wright), [1940?] (Box 98, Folder 1354)
    - Golden, Nan
    - Goodman, June, 1945 (Box 98, Folder 1355)
    - Gorelik, Mordecai, 1940-41 (Box 98, Folder 1356)
    - Goslitizdat, 1939-40 (Box 98, Folder 1357)
    - Gotham Book Mart, 1944-47 (Box 98, Folder 1358)
    - Gould, Walter, 1942-52 (Box 98, Folder 1359)
      Includes letter from Wright
    - Gourfain, Joyce, 1936-40, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1360)
    - G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1936, 1942, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1361)
    - Greater New York Chorus, 1942 (Box 98, Folder 1362)
    - Green, Paul, 1940-49 (Box 98, Folder 1363)
    - Greene, Mack, 1942-43 (Box 98, Folder 1364)
    - Gremley, William, 1946, 1950, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1365)
    - Grierson, John, 1942-50 (Box 98, Folder 1366)
    - Grünau, Werner von, 1958 (Box 98, Folder 1367)
    - Guérin, Daniel, 1950-56 (Box 98, Folder 1368)
    - Guggenheimer, Ida, 1944-46 (Box 98, Folder 1369)
    - Guth, Maë, 1946-47 (Box 98, Folder 1370)
    - "H" general, 1938-60 (Box 98, Folder 1371-1372)
    - Hairston, Jester, 1950-52 (Box 98, Folder 1373)
    - Håkansson, Lo, 1946-47 (Box 98, Folder 1374)
    - Hammett, Dashiell, 1941 (Box 98, Folder 1374a)
      Letters written on behalf of The Jewish Survey, also signed by Albert Maltz and Louis Harap
    - Hanson, Aquilla B., Jr., 1941-45 (Box 98, Folder 1375)
    - Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc., 1944-57 (Box 98, Folder 1376)
    - Harold R. Peat, Incorporated, 1941-46 (Box 98, Folder 1377)
    - Harper & Brothers Publishers, 1938-42 (Box 98, Folder 1378-1380)
    - Harper & Brothers Publishers, 1943-60 (Box 99, Folder 1381-1383)
    - Harper's Bazaar, 1939-40 (Box 99, Folder 1384)
    - Harper's Magazine, 1942-57
    - Harrington, Pam, 1956 Apr 29 (Box 99, Folder 1385)
    - Hayden, Robert, [1945?], 1957 (Box 99, Folder 1386)
    - Haygood, Vaudi, 1943, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1387)
    - Hays, Lee, 1939 Aug 5 (Box 99, Folder 1388)
    - Helem, Forbes, 19[43?]-45 (Box 99, Folder 1389)
    - Helion, Pegeen and Jean, 1959, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1390)
    - Hellman, Lillian, 1940-44 (Box 99, Folder 1391)
    - Herdman, Ramona
    - Hicks, Granville, 1938 Aug 25 (Box 99, Folder 1392)
    - Hill, Lawrence
      See: The Bookshop, A Consumer Cooperative, Box 94, folder 1224
    - Himes, Chester B., 1945-53, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1393)
      Includes letter from Ruth Seid (Jo Sinclair) to Himes
    - Holmes, Eugene
      See: The Bookshop, A Consumer, Box 94, folder 1224 Cooperative
    - Horne, Lena
      See: Lela Rogers, Box 105, folder 1581
    - Hoskins, Fred, 1945 Apr (Box 99, Folder 1394)
      Includes letter from Wright and clipping
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1939-45 (Box 99, Folder 1395)
    - Houseman, John, 1940-43 (Box 99, Folder 1396)
    - Howe, Russell, 1956 (Box 99, Folder 1397)
    - Hughes, Langston, 1936-60 (Box 99, Folder 1398)
      Includes copies of "Freedom Road" (sheet music) and "Sorrow for a Midget" (story, offprint), both signed by Hughes
    - Huntzbuchler, M.R., n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1399)
    - Huntley, Leston, 1940-45 (Box 99, Folder 1400)
    - Hurst, Fannie, 1941 Nov 19 (Box 99, Folder 1401)
    - "I" general, 1939-60 (Box 99, Folder 1402)
    - International Literature, 1936-42 (Box 99, Folder 1403)
    - Ivy, James W., 1951-58 (Box 99, Folder 1404)
    - "J" general, 1937-60 (Box 99, Folder 1405)
    - Jacobson, Harold, 1941-50 (Box 99, Folder 1406)
      See also: Paul R. Reynolds, Inc., Box 103, folder 1531
    - Jet
    - Jewish Survey
      See: Dashiell Hammett, Box 98, folder 1412
    - John Farquharson, Ltd, 1940-60 (Box 99, Folder 1407)
    - John Lane (Publishers)
      See: The Bodley Head, Box 94, folder 1216
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1938-50 (Box 99, Folder 1408)
    - Johnson, Charles Spurgeon, 1943-46 (Box 99, Folder 1409)
    - Johnson, Grace Nail, 1940-41 (Box 99, Folder 1410)
    - Johnson, Greer, 1940-45 (Box 99, Folder 1411)
    - Johnson, John
    - Johnson Publishing Company, 1944-58 (Box 100, Folder 1412)
    - Jolas, Maria, [1948?] Apr 3 (Box 100, Folder 1413)
    - Jones-Quartey, K.A.B., (Soas), 1953-58 (Box 100, Folder 1414)
    - Julius Rosenwald Fund
      See: Edwin Embree, Box 97, folder 1315
    - "K" general, 1939-60 (Box 100, Folder 1415)
    - Karpman, Benjamin, 1942-45 (Box 100, Folder 1416)
    - Kaufman, Wolfe, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1417)
    - Kennedy, Stetson, 1942-59 (Box 100, Folder 1418)
      (Includes copy of "On the Trail of- Man-haters behind the Curtain" typescript, photocopy, by Stetson)
    - Keys, Ulysses, 1938-41 (Box 100, Folder 1419)
    - Kier, Harvey, 1941-44 (Box 100, Folder 1420)
    - Kline, Herbert, 1945-60, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1421)
    - Knopf, Blanche
      See: Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., Box 93, folder 1166
    - Kongress für die Freiheit der Kultur, 1956, 1962 (Box 100, Folder 1422)
      See also: Claassen Verlag, Box 96, folder 1261
    - Koshland, William
    - Kosse, Albert and Ethol, 1944-53, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1423)
    - Kramer, Andres de, 1949-50 (Box 100, Folder 1424)
    - Kreymbourg, Alfred, 1941 Jan 28 (Box 100, Folder 1425)
      [Includes poem, "The Old South" (typescripts, carbon) by Kreymbourg, one signed]
    - "L" general, 1936-60 (Box 100, Folder 1426)
    - Lacob, Hannah, 1940-41 (Box 100, Folder 1427)
    - Lacroix, Colette, 1952-[53?] (Box 100, Folder 1428)
    - La Farge, Christopher
      See: Author's League of America, Box 94, folder 1193 - Author's Guild
    - Lambrecht, Klaus, 1940-41 (Box 100, Folder 1429)
    - Lamm, Hans, 1940, 1954 (Box 100, Folder 1430)
    - Lancaster, J. LeRoy, 1944 (Box 100, Folder 1431)
    - Langen, Eugen, 1959-60 (Box 100, Folder 1432)
    - Lanz, Esmé, 1948, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1433)
    - L.B. Fischer Publishing Corp., 1944-46 (Box 100, Folder 1434)
    - League of American Writers, 1935-[45] (Box 100, Folder 1435)
    - Lee, Canada, 1945, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1436)
    - Lee, Gypsy Rose, 1942 Dec (Box 100, Folder 1437)
    - Leiris, Michel, 1946 Jun 19 (Box 100, Folder 1438)
    - Lengyel, Melchior, 1949 (Box 100, Folder 1439)
    - Lescaze, Mary, [1946], n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1440)
    - LeSueur, Meridel, 1936 May 1 (Box 100, Folder 1441)
    - Les Lettres Nouvelles, 1954, 1960, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1442)
    - Lévi-Strauss, Claude, 1946-47 (Box 100, Folder 1443)
    - Librarie Gallimard, 1946-60 (Box 100, Folder 1444)
    - Lieber, Maxim, 1936-37 (Box 100, Folder 1445)
    - Liepman, Ruth, 1956-60 (Box 100, Folder 1446)
    - Life, 1945, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1447)
    - Ligue internationale contre le racisme et l'antisémitisme, 1951-56 (Box 100, Folder 1448)
    - Lindhardt, Helga, 1956-57 (Box 100, Folder 1449)
    - Lipper, Ruth, 1945 (Box 100, Folder 1450)
    - Lipton, Lawrence, 1941-42 (Box 100, Folder 1451)
    - Locke, Alain, 1938-40 (Box 100, Folder 1452)
    - Logan, Rayford, 1943 (Box 100, Folder 1453)
    - Lowenfels, Walter
    - "M" general, 1934-60 (Box 101, Folder 1454-1455)
    - Maas, Willard and Marie Menken, 1938-59 (Box 101, Folder 1456)
    - McClelland, Margaret
    - McConnell, William, 1944-46 (Box 101, Folder 1457)
    - McCullers, Carson, [1941?], 1947 (Box 101, Folder 1458)
      Includes letter from "Reeves"
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1947-56 (Box 101, Folder 1459)
    - MacGregor, Frank S.
    - McKay, Claude, 1946 Mar 12 (Box 101, Folder 1460)
    - MacKinnon, Clinton N., 1940-45 (Box 101, Folder 1461)
    - McLaren, Norman, 1941-46 (Box 101, Folder 1462)
      See also: Guy Glover, Box 98, folder 1352
    - MacLeod, Norman
      See: Young Men's Hebrew Association, Box 108, folder 1704
    - Magny, Claude-Edmonde, 1943 Jun 28 (Box 101, Folder 1463)
    - Maho, Jean, 1951 Jun 25 (Box 101, Folder 1464)
    - Malraux, André, 1947, [1960?] (Box 101, Folder 1465)
    - Maltz, Albert, 1945 Aug 23 (Box 101, Folder 1466)
    - Manhattan Life Insurance Co., 1954 (Box 101, Folder 1467)
    - Manhattanville College, 1939, 1941 (Box 101, Folder 1468)
    - Mantle, Burns
      See: Paul R. Reynolds, Inc., Box 103, folder 1531
    - Marcantonio, Vito, 1941, 1943 (Box 101, Folder 1469)
    - Martens, John S., [1946?], 1956 (Box 101, Folder 1470)
    - Marvin, Mark, 1943-51 (Box 101, Folder 1471)
    - Mascolo, Dionys
      See: Librarie Gallimard, Box 100, folder 1444
    - Mekeel, Scudder, 1944-45 (Box 101, Folder 1472)
    - Mercier, Louis
      See: Preuves, Box 100, folder 1444
    - Mezzrow, Mezz, 1946 May 20 (Box 101, Folder 1473)
    - Miller, Henry, 1946 Nov 3 (Box 101, Folder 1474)
    - Miller, Jesse, 1941, 1943 (Box 101, Folder 1475)
    - Modern Age Books, Inc., 1937-42 (Box 101, Folder 1476)
    - Mondadore, Arnoldo
      See: Arnoldo Mondadore, Editore, Box 93, folder 1184
    - Montgomery, Edmond and Fredrica, 1938-42 (Box 101, Folder 1477)
    - Moon, Henry Lee and Mollie, 1938-45 (Box 101, Folder 1478)
      See also: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Box 102, folder 1489
    - Moore, George, 1954, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1479)
    - Mosley, Jim S., 1952-57 (Box 101, Folder 1480)
    - Murphy, George
      See: National Negro Congress, Box 102, folder 1490
    - Myrdal, Gunnar and Alva, 1951-59 (Box 101, Folder 1481)
    - "N" general, 1935-60 (Box 101, Folder 1482)
    - Nabokov, Nicolas, 1959-60 (Box 101, Folder 1483)
    - Nadeau, Maurice, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1484)
      See also: Combat, Box 96, folder 1269
      See also: Les Lettres, Nouvelles, Box 100, folder 1442
    - Nassberg, Henry, 1947-54, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1485-1486)
    - Nat C. Goldstone Agency, 1940, 1942 (Box 102, Folder 1487)
    - The Nation, 1936-58 (Box 102, Folder 1488)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1938-59 (Box 102, Folder 1489)
    - National Negro Congress, 1936-43 (Box 102, Folder 1490)
    - National Sharecropper's Fund, 1945 (Box 102, Folder 1491)
    - Negro Digest
    - Negro History Project, 1939 Jan 23 (Box 102, Folder 1492)
    - Negro Story Magazine, 1944, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1493)
    - Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1955 Mar (Box 102, Folder 1494)
    - New Chorus, 1942 (Box 102, Folder 1495)
    - New Directions, 1957-58 (Box 102, Folder 1496)
    - New Masses, 1934-42 (Box 102, Folder 1497)
    - New Republic, 1935-56 (Box 102, Folder 1498)
    - New York Post, 1944, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1499)
    - New York Public Library, 1940-47 (Box 102, Folder 1500)
    - New York Times, 1944-49 (Box 102, Folder 1501)
    - Nichols, Constance Curtis, 1940, 1945, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1502)
    - Nin, Anaïs, [1947?] (Box 102, Folder 1503)
    - Nkrumah, Kwame, 1953 (Box 102, Folder 1504)
    - Norman, Dorothy, 1937-54 (Box 102, Folder 1505-1506)
      [Includes proofs for advertisement for Twice A Year featuring article by Wright]
    - North, Alex, 1940 Oct 29 (Box 102, Folder 1507)
    - North, Joseph
    - North, Sterling
      See: Chicago Daily News, Box 96, folder 1258
      See: Harper & Brothers Publishers, 1940, Box 98, folder 1378
    - Northe, James Neill, 1935, 1945 (Box 102, Folder 1508)
    - Nutt, Howard, 1935-41 (Box 102, Folder 1509)
    - N.V. Uitgeverij W. van Hoeve, 1956-60 (Box 102, Folder 1510)
    - "O" general, 1936-60 (Box 102, Folder 1511)
    - O'Brien, Edward J., 1935-39 (Box 102, Folder 1512)
    - Odets, Clifford, 1938-40 (Box 102, Folder 1513)
    - O'Hara, John, 1947 Mar 26 (Box 102, Folder 1514)
    - Oliver, Paul, 1957-60 (Box 102, Folder 1515)
    - Onstott, Kyle, 1960 (Box 102, Folder 1516)
    - Oswald, Marianne, 1945-48 (Box 102, Folder 1517)
    - Ovington, Mary White, 1940-41 (Box 102, Folder 1518)
    - "P" general, 1947-60 (Box 103, Folder 1519-1520)
    - Padmore, Dorothy, 1947-60 (Box 103, Folder 1521)
    - Padmore, George, 1946-59 (Box 103, Folder 1522)
      Includes letters to George Padmore from: Saul Blackman, C.L.R. James, J.H. Kelly and Frank Leach
    - Pagés, Pedro (Victor Alba), 1957 Oct 18 (Box 103, Folder 1523)
    - Panassié, Hugues, 1946-49 (Box 103, Folder 1524)
      Includes postcard signed by Louis Armstrong
    - Paris Review, 1953 Sep 3 (Box 103, Folder 1525)
    - Parker, Dorothy, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 1525a)
    - Parks, Gordon, 1944-49 (Box 103, Folder 1526)
    - Parry, Albert, 1939-45 (Box 103, Folder 1527)
    - Partisan Review, 1936-49, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 1528)
    - Patchen, Kenneth, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 1529)
    - Paul, Elliot, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 1530)
    - Paul R. Reynolds, Inc., 1938-44 (Box 103, Folder 1531-1535)
    - Paul R. Reynolds, Inc., 1945-72 (Box 104, Folder 1536-1540)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1942 Sep 24 (Box 104, Folder 1541)
    - Peat, Harold R.
      See: Harold R. Peat, Incorporated, Box 98, folder 1377
    - Peek, John T., 1940-41 (Box 104, Folder 1542)
    - Pelage, Sidney, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1542a)
    - P.E.N. Club, 1940-57 (Box 104, Folder 1543)
    - Pick, Ernest, 1960 (Box 104, Folder 1544)
    - Pippett, Roger
    - Pitts, Rebecca, 1935, 1937, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1545)
    - Pittsburgh Courier, 1942-56 (Box 104, Folder 1546)
    - Pivano, Fernanda, 1948-60 (Box 104, Folder 1547)
    - Plymouth Congregational Church, 1940-45 (Box 104, Folder 1548)
    - P.M. Daily, 1940-46, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1549)
    - Poetry, 1957 (Box 104, Folder 1550)
    - Polier, Justine Wise, 1945 (Box 104, Folder 1551)
    - Polacheck, Charles, 1941 (Box 104, Folder 1552)
    - Pool, Rosey E., 1946, 1959, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1553)
    - Pope, Arthur Upham, 1941, 1943 (Box 104, Folder 1554)
    - Porter, Russell M., 1948-55 (Box 104, Folder 1555)
    - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., 1940 Mar 5 (Box 104, Folder 1556)
    - Présence Africaine, 1947-59 (Box 104, Folder 1557)
    - Preuves, 1954-60 (Box 104, Folder 1558)
    - Prévost, Michel, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1559)
    - Pringle, Rosa, 1941-42 (Box 104, Folder 1560)
      Includes "Jethro" (story, printed) by Pringle
    - Pucciani, Oreste, 1947-48 (Box 104, Folder 1561)
    - "Q" general, 1943-47 (Box 105, Folder 1562)
    - Queneau, Raymond, [1947?] Dec 1 (Box 105, Folder 1563)
      See also: Librarie Gallimard, Box 100, folder 1444
    - Quinn, Anthony, 1958 Nov 13 (Box 105, Folder 1564)
    - Quinn, Kerker, 1936-42 (Box 105, Folder 1565)
    - "R" general, 1937-60 (Box 105, Folder 1566-1567)
    - Ragon, Michel, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1568)
    - Rahv, Philip
      See: Partisan Review, Box 103, folder 1528
    - Raiziss, [Harry?], n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1569)
    - Raiziss, Sonia, 1940-59
    - Random House, Inc., 1937-57 (Box 105, Folder 1570)
    - Raphäel, Maurice
      See: Series III, Franco-American Fellowship, Box 115, folder 1823
    - Reddick, Lawrence Dunbar, 1939-59 (Box 105, Folder 1571)
    - Redding, J. Saunders, 1942-45 (Box 105, Folder 1572)
    - Reif, David, 1940 (Box 105, Folder 1573)
    - Reinhardt, Max
    - Replansky, Naomi, 1942-47 (Box 105, Folder 1574)
    - République Française, 1947-48 (Box 105, Folder 1575)
    - Reynolds, Paul R.
    - Riker & Company, Inc., 1941 (Box 105, Folder 1576)
    - Riverdale Children's Association, 1945 (Box 105, Folder 1577)
    - Robeson, Eslanda Goode, 1939 (Box 105, Folder 1578)
    - Robeson, Paul, 1941 Mar 24 (Box 105, Folder 1579)
    - Rogan, Nathan, 1941 (Box 105, Folder 1580)
    - Rogers, Lela, 1944 Jul (Box 105, Folder 1581)
    - Roditi, Harold
      See: Dissent, Box 96, folder 1298
    - Rokotov, T.
      See: Walt Carmon, Box 95, folder 1250
      See: International Literature, Box 99, folder 1403
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1938-48 (Box 105, Folder 1582)
    - Rose, Innes
      See: John Farquharson, Ltd., Box 99, folder 1407
    - Ross, Sam, 1938-42 (Box 105, Folder 1583)
    - Rossellini, Roberto, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1584)
    - Rosskam, Edwin and Louise, 1941, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1585)
    - Rothschild, Connie Roy, 1945-46 (Box 105, Folder 1586)
    - Rouch, Jane, 1955 (Box 105, Folder 1587)
    - Rowan, Meyer, 1945-47 (Box 105, Folder 1588)
    - Rutherford, William A., 1947-53 (Box 105, Folder 1589)
    - "S" general, 1937-60 (Box 105, Folder 1590-1592)
    - Sablonière, Margrit de, 1954-60 (Box 105, Folder 1593-1594)
    - Saillet, Maurice, 1955 (Box 106, Folder 1595)
    - Salzman, Jacob, 1944-46 (Box 106, Folder 1596)
    - Sartre, Jean-Paul, [1947], 1960 (Box 106, Folder 1597)
    - Saturday Review, 1940-60 (Box 106, Folder 1598)
    - Schapiro, Louis, 1941-43 (Box 106, Folder 1599)
    - Schappes Defense Committee, 1941 (Box 106, Folder 1600)
    - Schorer, Mark, 1959 Feb 13 (Box 106, Folder 1601)
    - Schryver, Kit and Lee, 1939-56, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1602)
    - Scott, Virginia, 1940, 1944 (Box 106, Folder 1603)
      Includes "Not This Spring" (poem, typescript carbon by Scott
    - Seaver, Edwin, 1939-46 (Box 106, Folder 1604)
    - Seid, Ruth (Jo Sinclair), 1945-46 (Box 106, Folder 1605)
    - Seldes, Timothy
      See: Doubleday & Co. Inc., Box 96, folder 1301
    - Senghor, Léopold Sédar, 1946-59 (Box 106, Folder 1606)
    - Serreau, G.
      See: Les Lettres Nouvelles, Box 100, folder 1442
    - Sheldon, Edward, [1938], n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1607)
    - Sillcox, Luise M.
      See: Author's League of America, Box 94, folder 1193
    - Sillen, Sam
    - Silone, Darina, [1948-51?] (Box 106, Folder 1608)
    - Silone, Ignazio
      See: P.E.N. Club, Box 104, folder 1543
    - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1936-47 (Box 106, Folder 1609)
    - S.L. Gelband & Co., 1947 (Box 106, Folder 1610)
    - Smith, Jeanne, 1949-58, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1611)
    - Smith, Lillian, 1944 (Box 106, Folder 1612)
    - Smith, Milton, 1945-52 (Box 106, Folder 1613)
    - Smith, William Gardner, 1951, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1614)
    - Solé Cavallé, Jordi, 1950-51, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1615)
    - Soupault, Ré, 1946-53 (Box 106, Folder 1616)
    - Spender, Stephen, [1947?] Nov 17 (Box 106, Folder 1617)
    - Spingarn, Arthur, 1941, 1943 (Box 106, Folder 1618)
    - Stein, Gertrude, 1945 (Box 106, Folder 1619)
      Includes: letters by Joseph Barry and Henry A. Rago written on Stein's behalf
    - Steinberg Verlag, 1946-49 (Box 106, Folder 1620)
    - Stephan, Ruth, 1947 (Box 106, Folder 1621)
    - Stern, Arthur, 1940-42 (Box 106, Folder 1622)
    - Stoler, Elias, 1947-52 (Box 106, Folder 1623)
    - Storrs, Barrie, 1940 (Box 106, Folder 1624)
    - Story Magazine, 1936-56 (Box 106, Folder 1625)
    - Stout, Rex
      See: Author's Guild and Writers' War Board, Box 108, folder 1699
    - Strachey, John, 1957-59 (Box 106, Folder 1626)
    - Strauss, Harold
    - Street, Julian, Jr., 1944-45 (Box 106, Folder 1627)
      See also: United States. Treasury Department, Box 107, folder 1651
    - [Strong, Anna Louise?], 1949 Mar 20 (Box 106, Folder 1628)
    - Studin, Charles H., 1938-45 (Box 106, Folder 1629)
    - Syndicate of Czech Authors, 1948-49 (Box 106, Folder 1630)
    - "T" general, 1938-60 (Box 106, Folder 1631)
    - Taggard, Genevieve, [1938?]-43 (Box 106, Folder 1632)
    - Tal, Miriam, 1954, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1633)
      Includes: "Meeting Richard Wright in Paris" by Tal
    - Targ, William
    - TASS (Telegrafnoe agentstvo SSSR), 1941-42 (Box 106, Folder 1634)
    - Taub, Allen, 1941-45 (Box 106, Folder 1635)
    - Taylor, Frank
    - Les Temps Modernes, 1949, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1636)
    - Ten Eyck, Mills, Jr.
      See: Author's League of America, - Author's Guild, Box 94, folder 1193
    - Thomas, Winburn T., 1957, 1959, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1637)
    - Tillis, Fannie, 1940-41, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1638)
    - Time magazine, [1958] (Box 106, Folder 1639)
      Drafts of telegrams by Wright
    - Tolson, Melvin B., 1939-57 (Box 106, Folder 1640)
    - Trounstine, John J., 1936-37 (Box 106, Folder 1641)
    - "U" general, 1934-60 (Box 106, Folder 1642)
    - United States Air Force, 1957 (Box 107, Folder 1643)
    - United States. Civil Service Commission, 1941-42 (Box 107, Folder 1644)
    - United States. Department of State, 1940-46 (Box 107, Folder 1645)
    - United States. Embassy (various locations), 1944-60 (Box 107, Folder 1646)